<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Quasilinear Musings</title>
    <link>https://www.timlrx.com/tags/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Quasilinear Musings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>timothy.lin@alumni.ubc.ca (Timothy Lin)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>timothy.lin@alumni.ubc.ca (Timothy Lin)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.timlrx.com/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Regression - Method of Moments</title>
      <link>https://www.timlrx.com/2017/08/31/notes-on-regression-method-of-moments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>timothy.lin@alumni.ubc.ca (Timothy Lin)</author>
      <guid>https://www.timlrx.com/2017/08/31/notes-on-regression-method-of-moments/</guid>
      <description>Another way of establishing the OLS formula is through the method of moments approach. This method supposedly goes way back to Pearson in 1894. It could be thought of as replacing a population moment with a sample analogue and using it to solve for the parameter of interest.
Example 1To find an estimator for the sample mean, \(\mu=E[X]\), one replaces the expected value with a sample analogue, \(\hat{\mu}=\frac{1}{n}\sum_{i=1}^{n} X_{i} = \bar{X}\)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Regression - Projection</title>
      <link>https://www.timlrx.com/2017/08/23/notes-on-regression-projection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>timothy.lin@alumni.ubc.ca (Timothy Lin)</author>
      <guid>https://www.timlrx.com/2017/08/23/notes-on-regression-projection/</guid>
      <description>This is one of my favourite ways of establishing the traditional OLS formula. I remember being totally amazed when I first found out how to derive the OLS formula in a class on linear algebra. Understanding regression through the perspective of projections also shows the connection between the least squares method and linear algebra. It also gives a nice way of visualising the geometry of the OLS technique.
This set of notes is largely inspired by a section in Gilbert Strang’s course on linear algebra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Regression - OLS</title>
      <link>https://www.timlrx.com/2017/08/16/notes-on-regression-ols/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>timothy.lin@alumni.ubc.ca (Timothy Lin)</author>
      <guid>https://www.timlrx.com/2017/08/16/notes-on-regression-ols/</guid>
      <description>This post is the first in a series of my study notes on regression techniques. I first learnt about regression as a way of fitting a line through a series of points. Invoke some assumptions and one obtains the relationship between two variables. Simple…or so I thought. Through the course of my study, I developed a deeper appreciation of its nuances which I hope to elucidate in these set of notes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>