<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Musings on Quasilinear Musings</title>
    <link>https://www.timlrx.com/tags/musings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Musings on Quasilinear Musings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>timothy.lin@alumni.ubc.ca (Timothy Lin)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>timothy.lin@alumni.ubc.ca (Timothy Lin)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.timlrx.com/tags/musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Applications of DAGs in Causal Inference</title>
      <link>https://www.timlrx.com/2018/08/09/applications-of-dags-in-causal-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>timothy.lin@alumni.ubc.ca (Timothy Lin)</author>
      <guid>https://www.timlrx.com/2018/08/09/applications-of-dags-in-causal-inference/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionTwo years ago I came across Pearl’s work on using directed cyclical graphs (DAGs) to model the problem of causal inference and have read the debate between academics on Pearl’s framework vs Rubin’s potential outcomes framework. Then I found it quite intriguing from a scientific methods and history perspective how two different formal frameworks could be developed to solve a common goal. I read a few papers on the DAG approach but without fully understanding how it could be useful to my work filed it away in the back of my mind (and computer folder).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Musings</title>
      <link>https://www.timlrx.com/2018/04/28/statistical-musings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>timothy.lin@alumni.ubc.ca (Timothy Lin)</author>
      <guid>https://www.timlrx.com/2018/04/28/statistical-musings/</guid>
      <description>No technical details in this post. Just a few scattered thoughts and some stories that have kept me semi-entertained over the last month. Some are inspired by work and others are just my take on the world, exaggerated to some degree.
Rademacher CoinsAs we move towards a cashless society, maybe it would make sense to do away with coins and decimal values. Decimal points make billed amount and account balances unnecessarily messy and untidy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://www.timlrx.com/2018/02/11/february-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>timothy.lin@alumni.ubc.ca (Timothy Lin)</author>
      <guid>https://www.timlrx.com/2018/02/11/february-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Sorry about the lack of post over the past few month. Hope to regain some work life balance and update the blog more regularly. To start of the first blog post of 2018 I thought it would be nice to do share some interesting things that I have been reading over the past few weeks and create a to-do list to function as my commitment device.
Fun FactsDid you know that the skin color of a cat is heavily determined by a gene located on the X chromosome?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November Reflections</title>
      <link>https://www.timlrx.com/2017/11/05/november-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>timothy.lin@alumni.ubc.ca (Timothy Lin)</author>
      <guid>https://www.timlrx.com/2017/11/05/november-reflections/</guid>
      <description>A collection of thoughts to start the month off.
On the blog - Had a look at the google analytics data. There are about 750 views in total since the blog’s inception with a few users clocking in 5-10 minutes per post - so thank you for bumping up the stats if you are a regular reader!
The most popular post…is the SG dashboard. This was a little surprisingly. I thought my thesis or any of the mathy stuff is more interesting but who knows?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>